Guide to the Robert Hofstadter Papers SC0426
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2008-003
  - Awards and Honors
    - Mallinckrodt, Inc. Calendar, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Honorary Degree, University of Wurzburg, circa 1982 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Various Honors and Awards, circa 1981-1989 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Nobel Prize, Clippings from Palo Alto Times, circa 1961 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Event Programs (various), 1969-1987 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Honorary Degree, Russian, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences Fellowship, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Honorary Degree, Carleton University, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Honorary Degree, Johannes Gutenberg University of Mainz, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Honorary Degree, Gustabus Adolpus College, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Retirement Festivities, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - 70th Birthday Tribute by Robert Herman, 1985 March (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica, Reprint of Description, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Senior U.S. Scientist Award, Humboldt Foundation (Germany), 1981 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship, correspondence relating to the use of funds, 1974-1976 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Presidential Scholars Medal Dinner, White House Invitation, 1966 June (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Townsend Hans Medal, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - NASA Goddard Space Flight Center Group Award, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - City College of New York (CCNY) Alumnus, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Who's Who in the West 22nd Edition, Biographical Sketch, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - California Scientist of the Year, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - California Scientist of the Year, Invitation, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Guggenheim Fellowship, CERN (Geneva), 1958-1959 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Guggenheim Fellowship, Notification of Postponement for Sabbatical, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Incentive Awards (NASA), EGRET, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Event Programs and Publications, 1946-1976 (Box 25, Folder 31)
      Abba Eban (Israel) Dinner, Nobel Dedications, etc.
    - Major Magazines, 1961-1963 (Box 25, Folder 32)
      Time, Newsweek, Science, The Nobel Prize Magazine (full copies)
    - Nobel Prize, Clippings, circa 1961 (Box 25, Folder 33-34)
    - Scholarships/Fellowships, 1930-1946 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - California Scientist of the Year, correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Nominations for Tom Bonner Prize (A.P.S.), circa 1990 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - American Philosophical Society, Induction, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - National Medal of Science, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Biographical Materials
    - Nobel Laureates, The Examiner's Series (SF), circa 1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - "New Detectors for High-Energy Physics" (Science Magazine article featuring Hofstadter), 1969 June (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Biographical Correspondence and Clippings, circa 1961-1978 (Box 27, Folder 27)
      Draft letter to U.S. president about energy crisis; EGRET sticker, book review torn from magazine featuring Hostadter; clippings: May 17, 1978 Stanford Emeriti celebration
    - Dissertation, Princeton (copy made in 1973), 1938 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography for unknown manuscript, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Invention, Helmet and/or Torso Camera (Co-Inventor Dr. Joseph P. Kriss, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - CV in English and German, undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Last Will and Testaments, circa 1980 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Retirement Symposium, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Hofstadter writings on L.I. Schiff, 1950-1986 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Obituary from Radiology Magazine, 1991 May (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Diary with notes from phone conversations, 1980-1987 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Vita and Bibliography, 1989 Mar (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence to Nancy Hofstadter re: EGRET, circa 1991-1992 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Robert Herman foreword to Hofstadter's collected papers, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Books Donated to Stanford, list, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - CV, Bibliography and Personal Correspondence, undated (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, U.S. Government Draft and Selective Service Certification, 1940-1945 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Investment, Eli Lilly, Stock Information, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Condolence letters to Nancy Hofstadter -- S. and F. Fukui, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, notes, documents, circa 1940-1988 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Clippings
    - Clippings, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Electron Scattering, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - White House Dinner, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Nobel Prize, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
    - National and International Lectures, 1962-1966 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Various clippings, 1959-1962 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - "World of Electronics", 1988 Jul (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Various clippings, 1957-1958 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Various clippings, circa 1953-1987 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - National Medal of Science, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Various clippings, circa 1959-1967 (Box 26, Folder 12-13)
    - Clippings related to legal issues, circa 1955 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Nobel Prize, circa 1961 (Box 26, Folder 15-18)
    - GRO/EGRET, circa 1992 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Various international clippings, 1970-1974 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Various clippings, 1969, 1981, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Calendar, "The Founders of Nuclear Medicine", 1977 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Various clippings, circa 1950-1990 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence
    Incoming and outgoing correspondence of Robert Hofstadter. Included are chronological files of outgoing correspondence, as well as files arranged by correspondent or by topic.
    - Correspondence, outgoing institutional, 1962-1965 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 5-6)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 7-8)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, and telephone call notes, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 14-15)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1986 Oct-Dec (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1986 Apr-Jun (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1986 Jul-Sep (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1986 Jan-Mar (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with Publisher, "Exploring the Proton and Neutron", 1960-1966 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Grumman Aviation, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Correspendence from Hofstadter re: E. Barrie Hughes, undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, R.D. Cherry (University of Capetown, South Africa), circa 1959 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, Claudio Villa, 1958-1959 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, letters of complaint (non-academic), 1976-1989 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, University of Michigan, 1984-1985 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, letters of recommendation [restricted], 1960-1985 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, Stan Sobottka, nucleon structure, etc., circa 1958 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, NaI Crystals, circa 1955 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, President's Science Advisory Committee, 1964 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, Physik Verlag, 1959 Oct (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, job requests, 1959-1962 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, Peter Galison, "Big Science: The Evolution of Large-Scale Research", 1989 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, John McIntyre (Texas A&M), 1987 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, Kees, 1962 Nov (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, E.P. Winger (Clinton Laboratories, TN -- Monsanto Chemical Company), 1946-1947 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, Atomic Energy Commission, "Hydra Unclassified", circa 1954 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, Crystal Ball Project Scintillation Counters, circa 1950-1979 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, Scintillation Counters and Data Results, circa 1952 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, Atomic Acceleration, 1966 Aug (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence, Physics Department, 1958-1962 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, Crystals, Crystal Counters, etc, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, University Employment Negotiations/Options, circa 1946 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence, Consulting Positions, etc., 1946-1947 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence, National Bureau of Standards, 1943 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, Early Publications, 1945-1948 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, Post-War Job Search, circa 1946 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, Recommendation for A. Schalow, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence, International, circa 1958-1978 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence, Andrei Sakharov, circa 1980 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Various correspondence, 1950-1990 (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence, Professional/Corporate, 1950-1975 (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence, Extension of Mark III, 1962 Oct (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence, Pulsating Phenomena, NASA, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence, Gamma-Ray Astronomy, NASA, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Harshaw Chemical, 1966, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Harshaw Chemical, circa 1962-1973 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, proposals and related documents, Harshaw Chemical Co., circa 1965-1967 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Nobel Prize Congratulations, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Nobel Prize, 1960-1961 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Weizmann Institute, circa 1974 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Professors Constitution and HEPL, undated (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, W. Panofsky re: 2.5 GeV Spectrometer, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Electron Linear Accelerator, dispute with Norman Ramsey, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence. Nucleon-Unit Naming, "Rutherford" and "Yukawa" Discussion, CERN, circa 1959 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, SLAC, 1964-1975 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, Modernization of Hansen Laboratory, 1964-1965 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, Norden Labs, 1943-1946 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, SLAC, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, Navy requests and related matters, 1948-1954 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, proposals and various, 1960-1978 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, Warren Henry, 1955-1956 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, Navy Appointments, etc., circa 1940 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - KMS Fusion
    Correspondence, research documents, publications, reports, and promotional materials related to Hofstadter's work with KMS Fusion.
    - "KMS Industries Bets Its Life on Laser Fusion," Fortune Magazine, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - KMS Fusion miscellaneous, 1975-1979 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Congressional testimony and related documents regarding KMS principals, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - House of Representatives testimony, transcript and related documents, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Photographs and presentation materials, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, circa 1978 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, clippings, publications,, and related documents, circa 1977-1978, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
    - Laser hybrid, correspondence and related documents, circa 1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Clippings and related documents, circa 1974 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Henry Gomberg, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Laser Fusion at KMS Article, Advances in Internal Confinement Systems, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - KMS Fusion farewell letter drafts, circa 1980 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - KMS Fusion general, 1974-1979 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - KMS Fusion research and publications, 1972-1976 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - KMS Fusion slides, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Laser fusion, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Publications and Reports, 1975-1980 (Box 8, Folder 17-19)
    - Clippings and publications, 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Research and Correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box 9, Folder 2-6)
    - Correspondence and Publications, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Speech and notes on meeting with Lawrence Livermore, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lecture Notes and Teaching Materials
    Lecture notes and other materials related to courses taught by Hofstadter in the Stanford University Department of Physics. Included are audio and video recordings of Hofstadter's Physics 51 lectures, 1981-1983, plus a video recording of a 1978 lecture on laser fusion.
    - Physics 23: Electricity and Optics, 1964 winter (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Physics II, 1978 spring (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Physics II, 1981 spring (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Physics 51: Mechanics, Fluids and Sound, 1982 winter (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Physics 51: Mechanics, Fluids and Sound, 1981 winter (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Physics 51: Mechanics, Fluids and Sound, 1978 winter (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Physics 53: Electricity and Magnetism, 1983 spring (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Physics 51: Mechanics, Fluids and Sound, 1972 winter (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Physics 171: Statistical Mechanics, 1964 spring (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Physics 115, 1960 spring (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Physics 113: Introduction to Theoretical Physics, 1963 winter (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Physics III, 1960 winter (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Physics III, 1961 winter (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Physics 51: Mechanics, Fluids and Sound, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Physics 51: Mechanics, Fluids, and Sound, lecture supporting documents, 1978 winter (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Physics III, 1960 winter (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Physics III, 1959 winter (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Physics 113, 1960-1961 winter (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Physics 113, 1959-1960 winter (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Physics 115, 1961 spring (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Physics 115, 1962 spring (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Physics 113, 1961 spring (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Physics 212, 1963 spring (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Physics 171, 1965 spring (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Lecture notes and supporting documents, 1956-1986 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Physics 53: Electricity and Magnetism, 1985 spring (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Physics 51: Mechanics and Sound, 1956 fall and winter (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Physics 19, 1976 fall and 1977 winter (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Physics 57: Atomic Physics, 1969 winter (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Lecture Notes, 1976-1986 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Physics 23, exams and course documents, 1962-1964 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Physics 171, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Physics 23, 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Physics 242, 1968 spring (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Physics 51: Mechanics, Sound and Fluids, 1985-1986 (Box 19, Folder 6-7)
    - Physics 21: Mechanics and Heat, 1970 fall and 1971 winter (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Lecture Notes, unknown class, 1985-1986 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Physics 161, 1978 fall/winter (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Physics, Elementary Particle, 1967-1969 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Physics 11, 1985 winter (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Lecture notes, unknown class, undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Physics 53, 1983-1985 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Physics 53: Electricity and Magnetism, 1982, 1984-1985 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Physics 51, evaluation summary and select evaluations, 1979-1981 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Physics 51: Mechanics, Fluids and Sounds, 1983 winter (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Physics 51, evaluation summary and select evaluations, 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Physics II, 1985 winter (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Physics 53, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Lecture notes and correspondence, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Physics 240: Nuclear Physics, 1970 fall/winter (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Physics 250: Elementary Particle Physics, 1970 winter (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Physics 23, 1963-1965 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Nuclear Physics and Particle Physics, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - High Energy Physics, course readings, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Physics 185: Nuclear Physics I, course readings, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Physics 187: Nuclear Physics II, course readings, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Physics 194: Modern Physics Laboratory, 1950, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Physics 212, 1963 spring (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - E and M course, 1951 Jan-May (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Physics 51, circa 1955-1958 (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
    - Physics 51: Mechanics, Fluids, and Sound, 1981-1982 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Electron Scattering, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Physics 51, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Physics 51, 1982-1983 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Physics 51, 1980-1981 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Physics 131, 1975 winter (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Physics 51, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Physics 51, last class of term, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Physics 51, last class of term, 1982-1983 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Physics 250: High Energy Physics, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Physics 53, notes taken by ASSU lecture note service, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Physics 51, notes taken by ASSU lecture note service, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Lecture notes and course evaluations, 1964-1974 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Physics 51, notes taken by ASSU lecture note service, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Physics 170: Thermodynamics Block, Kinetic Theory, undated (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Physics 110: Intermediate Mechanics, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Physics 21: Mechanics and Heat, 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Physics 242: Elementary Particle Physics, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Physics 57: Atomic Physics, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Physics 242: Introduction to High Energy Physics, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - High Energy Nuclear Physics, course booklet, 1958 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Physics 130-131: Atomic Structure, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Physics 130, 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Physics 242/Physics 250, 1969 winter (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Physics 57: Atomic Physics, 1968 winter (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Physics 140: Nuclear Physics, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Physics 21: Mechanics and Heat, 1970-1971 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Physics 131, 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Physics 242: Introduction to High Energy Physics, 1967 spring (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Physics 132, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Physics 250/Physics 251: High Energy Physics, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Lecture notes, various, circa 1956 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Graduate student evaluations and recommendations, circa 1951 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Physics 161: Intermediate Optics, 1973-1979 (Box 21, Folder 18-19)
    - Physics 52 lectures, audio and video recordings, 1981-1983; (27 audiocassettes, 2 beta videocassettes, and 1 Umatic videocassette) (Box 31)
    - Laser fusion lecture, video recording, 1978 May 5; (1 videocassette) (Box 31)
  - Legal Papers
    - Patent, Shenier and O'Connor, 1965-1967 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Consulting contracts: Geographical Measurements Corp, National Radiac, Harshaw Chemical, 1957-1967 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Patent, Canadian Radium and Uranium Corp, "Coating", circa 1945 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Patents, various, 1946-1953 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Memorandum of Agreement, Princeton University (Academic Press, Inc.), Crystal and Scintillation Counters, 1949 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Scintillation Counter Dispute, Publications Cited by Defendant [Hofstadter] in Answer and Notice of Prior Art, circa 1956 (Box 27, Folder 6-7)
    - Scintillation Counter Dispute, Patents Cited by Defendant and Related Documents, circa 1956 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Patents, Hartmut Kallmann vs. Hofstadter re: radiation imaging tech, 1942, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - National Radiac and Fretco Inc., legal correspondence, circa 1951-1956 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - LARCO, Hofstadter vs. Ruderman, 1953-1955 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Forro-Seitz-Hilsch-Coltman, Iodine Impurity and Patent Debate, circa 1955 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Levinthal Electronic Products, Royalty Payment and Notification, 1957 Oct (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - LARCO, Hofstadter vs. Rudermann, decision, correspondence and related documents, 1953-1955 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Patent, Angiography Using Synchrotron Radiation, circa 1987 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Patents, various, 1944-1966 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Patents, correspondence and related documents, 1965-1968 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Physics of Sodium Iodide and Patent Amendment Affidavits, circa 1950-1952 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Notebook and Narrative, Discovery of NaI, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 19)
      Notebook (spiral) began in 1947, narrative 1955 -- see page 68 for significant development
  - Photographs
    Photographs of Hofstadter; professional events; and research equipment and facilities.
    - MARC III Linac, circa 1961-1964 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - San Francisco Chronicle photo shoot (also includes related correspondence), 1961 Nov (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Nobel Laureate Symposium, Princeton University, undated (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - EGRET, circa 1989-1992 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Lab and Equipment, circa 1957-1960 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - NaI(Tl), photographs and figures, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Crystal Conduction Counters, photographs and figures, undated (Box 27, Folder 26)
      Photographs of Hofstadter, research equipment, and facilities.
    - Additional photographs (Box 32-35)
  - Publications and Writings
    Drafts, notes, reprints, and other materials related to Hofstadter's published work. Researchers should note that much overlap exists between this subseries and the publications in Series 1.
    - Aborted Book on Nuclei and Nucleons, circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Includes manuscript "Exploring the Nucleon," remarks on manuscript from A.G. Julian, letter from Wiktor Osiatynski.
    - Draft for Text for Publication (unknown), circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Proton and Neutrons," draft, circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - "Proton and Neutrons," draft, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Proton and Neutrons," final draft for publication, circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Proton and Neutrons," handwritten drafts, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Reprints, 1950-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "The Atomic Nucleus," Scientific American, circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Publications, Featured and Translated (Russian), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Reprints, 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
      Subjects include electron scattering, spontaneous decay, and phase shifts.